This is pretty difficult.
Is this right?
Yes! That should be good!
Yours looks awfully big though?
Huh? Is it?
Are you making snacks for Shido and the others?
Yeah, that's right!
Mhmm. Right now, Master and the others
are preparing for the coming battle.
Wracking their brains is sure
to make them hungry.
Yoshino, Natsumi, would you like
to make some too?
It's fun!
Huh?
N-No I wouldn't...
Please let us help.
We want to be helpful to everyone.
Yoshinon's pads spout fire.
Huh?
You say a bunny doesn't have pads?
I hate clever brats like you.
Natsumi, you should join us, too.
I'm sure it'll be fun to do together.
Huh? But, u-umm...
Yes, yes, it's settled now.
Hurry up and get walking.
Come on, come on.
From far and wide,
non-erotic words that sound erotic!
Cockle!
Well... Bountiful.
Answer, sacks.
Huh?
Uhh, umm...
Machu Picchu?
Huh? Tell us a bit more about that, Kaguya!
How is Machu Picchu erotic?
I want to know too!
Please, inform us!
Demand. I seek an explanation.
What do you find sexually arousing
about a ruin of the Inca Empire?
Wh-Why are you only probing into my answer?!
Umm, because it sounds like...
Huh? Sounds like what?
I can't understand at all!
Explain. Please provide more detail.
I-It sounds like the sounds a kiss makes.
That's why?
Man, you're so cute, Kaguya-san.
Mercy.
Well, you seem to genuinely mean that,
so I'll accept it.
What are you being so evasive about?
All of you should explain yours, as well!
What's erotic about "cockles"?
Huh? It's close to co-
Ahh, could you please not explain!
Huh? After you told us all to explain?
Well, whatever.
Then let's continue.
Chincilla.
Uhh... "Bust".
Answer, six.
Ch-Chupacabra.
How is that erotic?!
Please tell us!
Confusion.
What aspect of a blood-sucking UMA from
South America brings you sexual arousal?
I don't want to play with you
guys any more!
Huh? Oh!
Then, from far and wide,
scenes where that boy was cool.
Huh?
For me,
I think it has to be when he refused to give up
on kissing me even when I was nearly dead.
He held me tight and went for it!
For me it was that one time.
The moment he risked his own life
to protect me from Inverted Tohka's
attack in the DEM Japan Branch.
Just remembering it reminds me how cool he was!
Proposal.
It was the time when he stopped me
and Kaguya from fighting.
Oh, not fair!
That's the one I was about to say!
We don't want to let that boy die, do we?
If it weren't for Darling,
I probably wouldn't be able
to trust anyone still.
Affirmative.
If not for Shido,
only Kaguya or I would exist
in this world, not both.
I would definitely be dead
if it wasn't for that boy.
Tohka
Cell Phone
Hmm, Tohka?
Call In Progress
Kaguya?!
We're making snacks for Shido
and the others right now,
but would you like to join us?
U-Umm, Yoshino here.
Yuzuru,
we're making snacks for Shido
and the others right now, but...
Nia?
It's Muku.
Come lend us a hand.
Sunday, February 18th
Natsumi
Help us make snacks
Ah! Natsumi, why are you the only one
to text instead of calling?!
Please let me hear your cute voice!
Shizaki, how's our requests for aid
to each branch going?
All sent.
I'll report once I have replies from each.
MARIA, have we finished
maintenance on our units?
There's essentially no issue,
but if I may be greedy,
I would like the Wizards to conduct
a manual inspection of the basic Realizers.
Also, I would like to request a wash
and wax for my outer plating.
We'll do something about the former,
but the latter is denied.
You're going to get disgustingly filthy
two days from now anyways.
In women, the heart is
the first thing to wane, Kotori.
What was that?!
Calm down, Kotori.
Why don't you take a break?
Thanks, I'll take it.
Sorry.
I wish there was something I could do, too.
What are you talking about?
I'm going to be assigning you
the toughest mission,
so you won't have the leeway to aid others.
Toughest mission?
Survive, no matter what.
I see.
You're certainly right about that.
Both DEM and Kurumi are targeting you.
I'm also worried about how Phantom will act.
Especially since we don't know
Phantom's identity
or what her goal behind making more Spirits is.
I can't help getting an ominous
feeling about that.
Phantom's goal, huh?
It might be something surprisingly silly.
Huh?
Snack time!
We made onigiri.
Eat to your heart's content.
Kotori
These are yours, Kotori!
Wow. Are there different ingredients inside?
Thank you.
Kotori?
What's wrong?
Cilantro?!
What is this, bullying?
You know I hate cilantro, right?!
We wanted to strengthen
our minds to help defeat DEM,
so we decided to try conquering our dislikes.
Even our own onigiri are filled
with things we don't like.
My onigiri has umeboshi!
Mine has pickled wasabi!
M-Mine has celery...
Go on!
You should overcome this trial, too, Shido!
Huh?
Shido
What... is in mine?
We really debated on your onigiri.
After all, there aren't many foods you dislike.
Affirmative.
Yours went through careful
consideration until the very end.
Darling, if you have trouble eating it,
then I'll help you!
S-So what is in mine, then?
At least tell me what you put inside it!
Shido?
Tohka, what's wrong?
Can't sleep?
Yeah.
Miku has awful sleeping habits.
She crawled over the floor like a caterpillar
and tried to sneak into my bed.
Was she really asleep, then?
What about you, Shido?
Yeah, I was thinking about Kurumi for a bit.
I will... make sure to save Kurumi.
I'll seal away her Spirit Power
and make her atone for her sins as best I could.
That's what I used to think.
But is what I consider salvation
truly salvation for Kurumi?
I don't know.
Kurumi is trying to save her best friend.
Is making her give up on that
really saving her?
I have to save Kurumi, no matter what.
But what should I be doing to achieve that?
What can I do for her?
Can I sit next to you?
Yeah, of course.
Huh? Huh?!
They did this on the TV's With Mother show.
Apparently it helps relax the mind.
Thank you, Tohka.
You're always helping me so much.
That's not true.
I have to apologize to you, Shido.
Huh?
When I heard that you would have
died if not for Kurumi,
I felt my chest tightening up.
Then I thought to myself,
"If I hadn't met Shido back then,
then Shido wouldn't have to face that."
Even now, you wouldn't be
stressing yourself this much.
Tohka.
What are you saying?
I'm truly happy that I met you that day.
But...
Sure I've faced danger, too,
but I've received so much
from you and all the Spirits.
Even if I could go back to our meeting
with all the memories I have now,
I would still reach out to you
without any hesitation.
Shido...
Good morning, everyone!
What great weather we have today, huh?
Morning, Tonomochi.
Wait, it's cloudy today.
Hey, have you heard anything from Itsuka?
No. He probably still has that cold.
But it's odd, isn't it?
Tokisaki has been absent the whole time, too.
That's so lame.
So have Tohka and Tobiichi, right?
You don't think they're being seduced
by sex-fiend Itsuka, do you?
Maybe all four of them
are on a hot springs trip!
That's so lame.
Come on, Itsuka of all people would never—
Do that?
No, it's plenty possible.
I'll tell you if I find anything out.
Thank you for your cooperation.
A spacequake?!
No way. Again?
That's so lame.
Come on, let's go to the school's shelter.
Yeah!
Hmm?
What's wrong, Tonomachi?
Well, did you see anything just now?
In the sky?
You saw something?
Hmm, it kind of looked like a battleship?
Tonomachi, have you finally damaged your brain?
No, he's become one of the boys
"who can see special things".
That's so lame.
Could you at least say those things
where I can't hear them?
That's strange, I know-
Tonomachi,
we're leaving you behind!
Ah, wait up for me!
The DEM fleet has emerged.
Their fleet numbers roughly thirty ships!
That's nearly every ship DEM possesses.
Looks like our intel was accurate.
How's the city?
Residents have completed evacuation.
There's no one on the surface.
Good. Now we can fight without holding back.
This is Fraxinus Commander, Kotori Itsuka.
First, I'm truly grateful
for all your cooperation.
An insolent visitor has arrived in our city.
They're the lowest,
scummiest kind of abusive man
who tries to steal the power of Spirits
through rough and violent means!
Yeah. Hate it, right? Well beyond deplorable.
Men who try to dominate
women through force like that
are always the kind who cowardly
cling to them when abandoned.
Now! Let's teach these
ill-mannered thugs a lesson!
Teach them the proper way to treat women.
Teach them how to elegantly escort a woman.
Teach them how we conduct our dates!
Roger!
Yeah!
What incredible fervor.
Yeah, Kotori was cool, too!
It is the commander's job
to raise everyone's morale.
Though we only have six ships
against our enemy's aerial fleet of 30.
On top of that, they have several
thousand Bandersnatch, too.
Plus we have no idea
how many Nibeelcole will pop up.
But you Spirits are the key
to overcoming this situation.
I know it might be wrong for the leader of
an organization dedicated to protecting Spirits
to ask those very same Spirits for their help,
but please.
Please lend us your power.
I ask you as the commander of Ratatoskr, no,
I ask you as Shido's little sister,
please save my older brother!
Of course!
Please let us help, too.
That's right!
In fact, we'd be angry
if you tried to leave us out!
Raising morale is a commander's job?
Then you're quite
the commander now, little sister!
Yes. Kotori is the only commander
who can lead us!
Affirmative.
I'm willing to place
our lives in Kotori's hands.
Everyone...
Nia, it's okay to hold a strategy
meeting here now, right?
Yeah. I'm jamming Beelzebub.
Even if he tries to peek at our
situation now, he won't make it in time.
So, what evil plots do you have?
Proposal. Why don't we use Mukuro's Michael
to link spaces and storm
the enemy's command center?
Ah, I knew we were thinking the same thing!
I just didn't say it because
we couldn't speak it out loud.
Sorry, but that might be impossible.
Ever since Master sealed away my Spirit Power,
I've had difficulty
with long-range teleportation.
Even if it were possible, I wouldn't permit it.
Our enemy is naturally wary of that,
and we have no idea
what kind of traps they've set for it.
The Bandersnatch are being operated
by DEM's new Realizers, Ashcroft β.
They were created using
Artemisia Ashcroft's brain as their model.
What did you say?
Artemisia?
Wait, the Wizard that was with Ellen?
She was originally the ace
of Britain's Anti-Spirit Team.
DEM succeeded in integrating
a control function into the Realizers
after tracing her brain.
MARIA, if we captured her,
would it be possible for you
to use her brainwave data to create
a jamming code for the Ashcroft β?
Yes. It would likely be possible.
She was always skeptical
about the way DEM does things.
And now I think she's only obeying DEM
because they've manipulated her memories.
If we push there,
I think we have a good chance of capturing her.
I see. Got it.
MARIA, you sounded like you had a strategy, too?
Yes.
There is a way to render
the Nibeelcole powerless.
Though to do so,
we'll need to have Shido on the front lines.
You need Shido?
You know I can't ever permit that!
This battle is all about protecting Shido!
Yes.
However, we cannot win if we
don't do something about the Nibeelcole.
But still...
No, let's do it.
Let me hear your plan, MARIA.
Shido...
All right.
But before that, let's go show them
just what it means to fight us in this city!
It would seem Nightmare
passed along my message.
It looks like Ratatoskr
is deploying all their forces, too.
Wise decision.
They have no chance of winning
if they don't take the offensive here.
They're most likely intending
to come after my head and yours.
It's well known that DEM
would collapse if it lost us.
In that case, Ike,
shouldn't you be in a safer location?
We started this revolution.
So I can't allow you to be
the only one standing at its front.
Now, shall we begin, Captain?
Yes, sir!
All ships, launch the first wave
of Bandersnatch!
Magic cannons, prepare to fire!
Target Ratatoskr's aerial battleship!
An attack from Ratatoskr?!
It's not! This is—!
Attention, please.
Can you hear me, vile Wizards?
Nightmare!
Starting now, I'm coming to hunt you all down.
Do please try not to flee.
What?!
Ship 2, Honorius! Ship 3, Notoria!
Cover the Bandersnatch squad!
What?! What happened?!
It looks like we've been hit
with cannons from the surface!
From the surface?
What is going on with this city?!
Let's accept their challenge.
All we need do is remain calm
and lower our fist with full force.
Episode 2
Final Respite
Episode 3   "The Spirit's Resurrection"
And so the battle has begun.
What is the new combat strategy
Shido employs against Nibeelcole?
Next Episode is Episode 3:
"The Spirit's Resurrection."
The most powerful Spirit now manifests itself.